

About Me

Passionate software developer with 4+ years of experience, an appetite for problem-solving and curiosity into how things work.

Front end development is where I am strongest, building out clean, effective UI / UX. I also work across the rest of the stack, comfortable adding functionality and fixing issues wherever I'm needed.

Skills

- .NET / ASP.NET
- C# / Azure
- Angular / AngularJS
- JavaScript / TypeScript
- CSS / Sass
- HTML

Achievements

Udemy - 2023

Angular - The Complete Guide

Microsoft 2021

AZ-204: Azure Developer Associate

languages

English (Native)

Japanese (B1)

JONATHAN RACE

Software Developer

Phone 07792331478

Email

jonathanrace7@gmail.com

Location

Nottingham, UK

Experience

Full Stack Web Developer

2024 - Ongoing

CCHQ

- Co-led the initial architecture and design of an AngularJS to Angular migration to improve front-end security.
- Optimized stored procedures / SQL query plans to improve performance under high load.
- Implemented multiple features / enhancements in ASP.NET / C# to improve user experience and speed up common workflows in the business.

Front End Web Developer

2020 - 2023

senso.cloud

- Played a significant role in the early stages of rewriting an ASP.NET MVC safe-guarding application to Angular, contributing to the architectural design and implementation in the front end.
- Led a "Simplified View" project that was aimed at creating a more minimal / user-friendly UI to customers.
- Worked on cloud-based, remote monitoring functionality, utilising SignalR to enable users to remotely monitor multiple devices at once from a browser.
- Used Azure functions to automate various tasks used in the software.
- Wrote several core UI components from scratch (datetime picker,tile-shuffler etc) saving the business licensing costs from 3rd party libraries and adding enhanced customisability.
- Added extra functionality to a Xamarin based mobile app, allowing users to add bookmarks and use multiple tabs in a built-in custom web browser.

Front End Web Developer

2019-2020

Upwork

- Created Wordpress site from Photoshop designs using Elementor and custom CSS / JavaScript.
- Developed JavaScript code for rendering tiles on a canvas element in a tile-based game, dynamically generating visuals based on input from the game logic.
- Designed and built several websites based on brief from clients, using HTML, CSS and JavaScript

Interests

- Outside of software development I enjoy the problem solving and physical challenge of bouldering.
- I also enjoy producing electronic / cinematic music and have supported a number of big names live while DJ'ing in the past.
- On top of this I have been selfstudying Japanese for around 6 years and hope to take the JLPT tests in the future.

Driving Licence

Full, clean UK driving licence

References

References are available on request

Education

Developer Certification

2019 - 2020

freeCodeCamp

 Completed several modules including: Applied visual design, Applied accessibility, Bootstrap, Responsive web design, JavaScript algorithms and data structures, jQuery, React, Redux, and Sass.

Developer Certification

2019 - 2020

Codecademy

• Studied the courses 'Introduction to JavaScript' and 'Learn PHP'.

Music Technology FdSc

2008 - 2010

De Montfort University

- Gained a deep understanding of audio signal processing, developing my engineering / problem solving skills.
- Learned creative thinking skills helping with design and 'thinking outside the box'.